Tom Spring

Full Stack Engineer - UK tomspring5000@gmail.com / 07758 600167 github.com/tspring5000 linkedin.com/in/tom-spring5000/

I am a highly motivated engineer with a strong proven track record of managing large corporate platforms and leading internal product development programs. I enjoy building relationships with external clients and internal teams, and have considerable experience of developing my and others capabilities.



Expert: Django / Python / Vue / REST / Git

Intermediate: Go / Typescript / React / Swift / Zig / Linux / AWS

Experience

Career Break (Jan 2023 - Present)

- Took a year out to travel in South East Asia, covering Thailand, Vietnam, and Cambodia
- Also used the time learning new technologies; Svelte, Flutter and Rust to name a few
- · Launched first iOS app 'Nonatone'

Full Stack Engineer @ The Access Group (Apr 2019 - Dec 2022)

- Django, Python, Vue, DRF, Git, Linux, AWS
- Responsible for managing recruitment candidate screening platform for over 200 corporate clients
- Experience of leading product enhancement projects, for example implementation of a medical check feature allowing us to process medically trained candidates at the critical time of COVID19
- Experience consuming and building API's, for example, I led an ambitious rewrite of the public API with the goal of reaching feature parity with the front-end and improving documentation coverage
- Accountable for management of sensitive data, for example, executed a migration of client billing information to a new system, automating the previously intensive work of keeping up with bespoke contracts
- Onboarding new starters to the development team of all experience levels and mentoring junior/mid-level engineers.

Data Analyst @ Corporate Software Services, Inc (Sep 2017 - Mar 2019)

- SQL, Python, Elasticsearch, Splunk, PowerBI, Selenium
- Managed data, reporting and web testing for external clients
- Developed data pipelines using Python and various API's

Education

- BTEC Level 3 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT and Telecoms Professionals (2016 Apprenticeship)
- BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma in ICT Systems and Principle (2016 Apprenticeship)
- ITIL Foundation Certification Training Level (2018)

★On the Side

Mobile Apps: Recently I've been working on a synthesiser app for iOS called <u>Nonatone</u>, which has been very well received in the small time its been out for.

I have also been working on an experimental sleep app using Flutter, which has even taken me so far as learning Arduino as a prototyping platform

Game Development: Game dev has been a side project for me since I started learning programming, and I've been working on a large side project for a few years now. My tech stack consists of Godot and Aseprite right now, but in the past I've used everything from Unity to Blender to PICO-8 and even a few frameworks such as Bevy (Rust). As I work solo most of the time, I'm always having to pick up new skills aside from programming, including art and music as well as project and time management

Music: Branching off from a need for game dev to its own hobby entirely, I also make music as a side project. Right now I'm trying out live coding, such as Glicol, for a programmatic approach to composition